اَعُوْذُ بِاللهِ مِنَّ الشِّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيْمِ۝
بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمَانِ الرَّحِيْمَ۝
اَلْحَمْدُ لله  وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْراً
This is session number two,
we'll carry on In Sha Allah Ta'ala(اِنْ شَاء الله تعالى) with Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) in Makkah, we are still in Makkah.
We talked about his Islam in the last session and the Dua(دُعَا) of Rasool Allah ﷺ for him,
اَلَلَّهُمَّ اَعِزَّ الْاِسْلَامَ بِأحَبِّ الرَّجُلَيْنِ اِلَيْكََ
O Allah! Give Islam strength, and power through the most beloved of the two men to You,
Amr Ibn Hisham(عمرو بن هشام) or Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) and Allahعزُّوْجل chose Umar(عمر).
So, Umar(عمر) became Muslim and he grew into Islam to become the second greatest after Abu Bakr As-Siddiqueرضي الله عنه,
while Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) chose the other course
and that is to be the Fir’auon(فرعون), of this Ummah(امة).
لِكُلٍّ وِجْهَةٌ هُوَ مُوَلِّيْها
Everyone chooses a path.
Now, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) being the man he is,
he didn’t want the event of his Islam to go un-noticed.
You know, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) was a man for the Ummah(اُمَة).
Some people; you know, they want to do their Salah(صلاة) and do their small individual Ibadaat(عبادات)
and stay out of trouble, stay out of Islamic work, don’t do anything, just pray, and do your fasting and be calm, and don’t be noticed,
that's not Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب).
Some people they just care about themselves, and their family,
as long as I am alright, and my family is alright, then everything is good, everything is okay.
But Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) wasn't such a person.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) saw that Muslims were been tortured, he wants to be like them.
He saw that, they are being persecuted, he wants to be like them.
He cared for the Ummah(امة) and that's why Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) was a statesman by nature.
He had the virtues of a Khalifah(خليفه).
Because he was very, very concerned with the Ummah(امة)
he was a man for the Ummah(امة), what pleases them, pleased him
and what displeases them, displeased him.
And that's why, when Abu Bakr As-Siddiqueرضي الله عنه appointed him Khalifah(خليفه),
that's in fact, that's the statement that Abu Bakr(ابو بكر) made.
He said: He is a man who is pleased when the Ummah(امة) is pleased
and he is displeased when the Ummah(امة) is displeased.
Umar(عمر) wasn't a selfish person, who is only caring about himself and his direct family,
like many of the Muslims today are.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرإبن الخطاب) wanted to join the Ummah(امة) in their happiness and in their pain.
When he saw Rasool Allah ﷺ and Abu Bakr(ابو بكر) crying, he came and he said:
Tell me, why are you crying?
If it makes me cry otherwise, I will force myself to cry.
So, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) did not want his Islam to go un-noticed.
So, where does he go, which house does he choose to go to?
The house of Abu Jahal(ابوجهل).
He goes to the house of Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) and knocks his door.
Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) opens the door and says; Welcome Ibn Al-Khattab(ابن الخطاب)! Welcome!
Because he didn't know that he became Muslim yet.
And they used to love Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) because of his dedication to the persecution of the Muslims.
So, he said: Welcome Son of Al-Khattab(ألخطاب),
Umar Ibn Khattab(عمربن خطاب) said: I became a Muslim, for your information.
Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) said: What! He said: I have became Muslim.
Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) said: Don’t do so!
Umar(عمر) said: Well I did!
Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) slammed the door in his face.
Umar(عمر) said:
مَا هَذَا بِشَيْ
This is nothing, this is not, what I am looking for?
Because Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) wanted to be like the rest of the Ummah(امة)
but no one in their sane Mind in Quraish(قريش), no matter how much they hate Islam
was willing to take over the task of torturing Umar(عُمَر) even Abu Jahal(ابوجهل).
Abu Jahal(ابوجهل) did not want to deal with it, so he just closed the door.
Umar(عمر) went to another house, knocking the door, welcome son of Al-Khattab(الخطاب)
I became a Muslim.
He said: Don’t do so!
لَاتَفْعَلْ ،
فَعَلْتْ
I did so, he closes the door.
So, there was somebody, who was watching what Umar(عمر) was doing.
He went to Umar(عمر) and he said:
It seems that you want people to know that you have became a Muslim?
He said: Yes!
He said: Do you see that man over there?
Go to him and tell him that you have became Muslim and that's all what you need.
He was pointing towards Jameel Bin Mu'ammar Al-Jum'hi(جميل بن معمر الجمهي)
Jameel Bin Mu’ammr(جميل بن معمر) is a man, who cannot hold any water in his mouth,
he was a mobile transmitter, a living broadcasting station.
So, he goes to him, and he says:
يَا جَمِيْل لَقَدْ اَسْلَمْتُ
O Jameel(جميل), I have became a Muslim.
Abdullah Bin Umar(عبدالله بن عمر), said: I was watching my father.
He Said: When he told Jameel(جميل) that he became Muslim,
Jameel(جميل) immediately, stood up, without saying anything, he just stood up, sprang up,
dragged his Izaar(إزار) and walking briskly towards Al-Ka’aba(ألكعبه), where everybody is meeting,
and then he says: Ya Quraish(يا قريش)! O people of Quraish(قريش)!
Umar(عمر) embraced Islam, Umar(عمر) embraced Islam, Umar(عمر) embrace Islam.
The news was all over, breaking news all over Makkah.
That's all, what Umar(عمر) needed to do, is to tell Jameel(جميل).
In fact, the narration says, that Jameel(جميل) wasn’t saying that Umar(عُمَر) was Muslim.
He was saying Saba'a(صبأ)’
and Saba'a(صبأ) was a derogatory term, the people of Quraish(قريش) used to use when somebody would become Muslim.
So, Umar(عمر) was following the Jameel(جميل) trying to correct the information
but when it gets on the front page of a newspaper, it's too late.
Jameel(جميل) was just running all over, saying Saba'a Umar(صبا عمر), Saba'a Umar(صبا عمر)
and Umar(عمر) is trying to correct the information, he's saying,
بَلْ اَسْلَمْت، بَلْ اَسْلَمْتُ
but there is nothing you could do.
Now, Jameel(جميل) did it for Umar(عمر).
The mobs just attacked from every direction and Umar(عمر) is, in between them fighting for himself
and they are attacking him and he is getting hits from every side.
What does, Umar(عمر) do?
He grabs Ut'bah Bin Rabiya(عتبة بن ربيعه), who is one of their noble men
throws him to the ground sits on top of him and then he sticks his fingers in his eyes.
So, Utba’ah(عتبة) screams and then everybody backs off.
Abdullah(عبدالله) said: So when he released Utba’ah(عتبه) and he walked away the mob attacked him again.
فَجَعَلَ كُلَّمَا
Abdullah Ibn Umar(عبدالله إبن عمر) says; Whenever, the mob would attack him,
he would grab the most noble man, he sees in front of him and stick his fingers in his eyes, until they back off.
And that kept on happening again and again.
He said: Eventually Umar(عمر) could not fight any further.
People are attacking him from every direction.
So, he just sat down, while people were hitting him and then he said:
وَاللهِ لَوْ كُنَّا ثَلَاثَ مِائَة لَتَرَكْنَهَا لَكُمْ اَوْ تَرَكْتُمُوْهَالَنَا
If we were but three hundred strong, you would either leave it for us, or we would leave it for you!
And this was a very Prophetic Statement.
What Umar(عمر) was saying is, if we were three hundred strong,
if the Muslims were three hundred strong, we would fight you
and either you leave Makkah or we leave it for you.
And Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), the order of Jihad(جهاد) was given, Qitaal(قتال),
and the first army to meet Al-Kuffr(الكفر) was three hundred and thirteen, in Badr(بدر).
So, as if Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) was waiting for it, but the numbers were not ready yet.
We are gonna fight you, but we were few.
And the narration says that Muslims were about forty in Makkah, when Umar(عمر) became Muslim.
Allah o Alam(الله اعلم), if that includes the Muhajireen(مهاجرين) of Al-Habasha(اَلْحَبَشَه) or not.
Because the majority of Muslim actually made Hijrah(حجرة) to Al-Habasha(اَلْحَبَشَه).
Umar(عمر) went to Daar-Ul-Arqam(دار الارقم) and he asked Rasool Allah ﷺ, he says;
أ لَسْنَا عَلَى الْحَقِّ اِنْ حَيِيْنَا وَاِنْ مِتْنَا
Aren’t we on the right path, whether we live or die?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Yes!
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر إبن الخطاب) said:
فَلِمَ الْإخْتِفَاءُ اِذَاً؟
Then why, should we hide?
Why should our Islam be, underground, why are we hiding?
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ agrees with Umar(عمر) and he arranges the Muslims in two ranks
and Rasool Allah ﷺ is standing between these two ranks,
and one rank is headed by Umar(عُمَر) and the other by Hamza(حمزه).
And they marched down the streets of Makkah declaring,
أشْهَدُاَنْ لَّأ اِلَهَ اِلَّا الله وَ أشْهَدُ اَنَّ مُحَمَّدًا رَسُوْلَ الله
That was the public declaration of Islam in Makkah
and it happened when Umar(عمر) and Hamza(حمزه) became Muslims.
And the difference in time between their Islam according to one narration was three days.
The narrator says; When they reached to Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه)
and the people of Quraish(قريش) saw Umar(عمر) and Hamza(حمزه),
اَصَابَتْهُمْ كَآبَة لَمْ تُصِبْهُمْ قَطْ
They were depressed, like never before.
Because now, they've seen strength that Allah has given to Islam through Hamza(حمزه) and Umar(عُمَر).
And that's the day, in which Umar(عمر) was given the name Al-Farooq(اَلْفَارُوْقْ) by Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Al-Farooq(اَلْفَارُوْقْ), the Criterion, he is the criterion of Haqq(حق) and Batil(باطل).
He is the criteria that separated between the truth and falsehood.
Al-Farooq(اَلْفَارُوْقْ) Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) this name was given to him by Muhammadﷺ.
The Islam of Umar(عمر) had great impact on the early Islamic Movement.
Abdullah Ibn Masood رضي الله عنه says;
مَا زِلْنَا اَعِزَّةْ مُنْذُ اَسْلَمَ عمر وَلَقَدْ رَأيْتَنَا وَمَا نَسْتَطِيْعُ اَنْ نَطُوْفَ بِالْبَيْتِ
حَتَّى اَسْلَمَا عمر فَلَمَّا اَسْلَمَ قَاتَلْنَاهٌمْ حَتَى تَرَكُوْنَ فَصَّلَّيْنْا وَطُفْنَا
He said: We became powerful when Umar(عُمَر) became Muslim,
before we were not able to even make a Tawaf(طواف) around the house of Allah or Pray.
When he became Muslim we fought them, until they allowed us to Pray and make Tawaf(طواف) around Al-Ka’aba(ألكعبه).
He also says;
كَانَ الاِسْلَامُ عمر فَتْحاً وَهجْرَتُه’ نَصْراً وَإمَارَتُه رَحْمَهَ
وَلَقَدْ رَاَيْتَنَا وَمَا نَسْتَطِيْعُ أن نصَلِّى وَنَطُوْفَ بِالْبَيْتِ حَتَّى اَسْلَمَ عمر
فَلَمَّا اَسْلَمَ قَاتَلْنَاهُمْ حَتَّى تَرَكُوْنَا نُصَلِّى
He said: The Islam of Umar(عُمَر) was an opening
and his Hijrah(هجرة) was a victory, and his reign was mercy,
and we weren't able to pray publically, until he became Muslim.
Suhaib Ar-Romi(صهيب الرومى) says;
لَمَّا اَسْلَمَ عمر ابن الخطاب رضى الله عنه ظَهْرَالْاِسْلَامْ وَدُعِيَ إلِيْهِ عَلَانِيَّةَ
وَجَلَسْنَا حَوْلَ الْبَيْتِ حِلَقًّا وَطُفْنَا بِالْبَيْتِ وَانْتَصَفْنَا مِمَّنْ غَلَظَ عَلَيْنَا وَرَدَدْنَا عَلَيْهَ
When Umar(عُمَر) became Muslim Islam became public
and we used to invite to Islam publically, and we use to sit in circle around the House of Allah
and we use to make Tawaf(طواف) around the House of Allah
and we started getting even, with the ones, who oppressed us.
All of that because of the Islam of one man, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab رضي الله عنه.
According to As-Sayuti(السيوطي) the age of Umar(عُمَر) when he became Muslim was twenty seven years old,
which is younger than the earlier narration which would be in his thirties
but that’s the rough estimate of the age of the Umar(عُمَر), when he became Muslim, so he was young.
WHAT ABOUT HIS HIJRAH(هجرة)?
Ibn Abbas(ابن عباس) said: Ali Ibn Abi Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب) told me,
that every Muslim made Hijrah(هجرة) secretely except Umar(عُمَر).
When he wanted to make Hijrah(هجرة), he hung his sword on his neck
and he threw his bow over his shoulder, and he had a baton hanging from his waist,
and he has his hand full of arrows, fully loaded.
And then he walked to Al-Haram(الحرم) to Al-Ka'aba(ألكعبه) and he made Tawaf(طواف).
Now, all the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) were sitting around Al-Ka'aba(ألكعبه)
Umar(عُمَر) was making a Tawaf(طواف).
Now, the key word that Ali(علي) says:
مُتَمَكِّنا
with the confidence.
You know, because sometimes you could be going to a fight and you are putting up a strong face, while inside you are trembling,
and you are saying: Yea! Yea! It's alright! It's fine! I am ready for it! I am ready for it!
And inside you are shaking.
But Ali(علي) said: Mutamakinan(متمكناً), he was so confident and at ease, about it.
فَطَافَ مُتَّمَكِّنًاَ
He made Tawaf(طواف) around the House with confidence.
And then he stands behind the Maqaam-e-Ibraheem(مقام ابراهيم) and he prays.
Ali Ibn Abi Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب) said;
The leaders of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) were sitting in circles around Al-Ka'aba(ألكعبه).
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) goes to those circles, one by one and he stands on top of every circle, and he says;
شَاهَتُ الْوُجُوْهَ
May these faces be disfigured!
وَلَا يُرْغِمُ اللهُ إلَّا هَذِهِ الْمَعَاطِسْ
May Allahعَزّ وجَلّ humiliate these noses in the dirt!
And then, he did not even use the word noses which is Aanf(أنْف), he said Ma’atis(معاطس)
which is like, he is telling them the organ which you sneeze with.
He is making, even fun of their noses, he said:
هَذِهِ الْمَعَاطِسْ
and then he said:
مَنْ اَرَادَ أَنْ يُثْكِلَ اُمَّهّْ
The one, who wants his mother to be bereaved, and his wife to be a widowed
and his children to be orphaned, come and meet me behind that valley.
If you want your mother to cry for the loss of her son
and your wife to live as a widow and your children to be orphans,
come and meet me behind that valley.
Ali Ibn Abi Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب) said: No body stood up
except some of the fools of Makkah and he taught them, a very good lesson, before they went back home.
Only Umar(عُمَر) made Hijrah(هجرة) publically, everyone else made it in hiding.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) had made an appointment with two of his friends.
Ayaash Ibn Abi Rabi’a(عيَّاش اِبن ابي ربيعه) and Hisham Ibn Al-Haris(هشام ابن حارث)
that they are gonna meet in this place outside of Makkah
and they are gonna be accompanied on the journey to Madina.
And they said: We meet at this place
if you do not show up by this time, it means that something happened, you were arrested or something
so whoever, is there would leave.
So, at the appointed time Umar(عُمَر) and Ayaash(عياش) were there, Hisham(هشام) wasn't.
And Hisham(هشام) was arrested and Umar(عُمَر) says:
فُتِنَ فَافْتُتِنْ
They put him in tribulations, and he left Islam.
So, the others two headed to Madina, Umar(عُمَر) and Ayaash(عياش).
They reached to Quba'a(القُباء) or Qiba'a(قِبَاء), both are correct,
which is outside Madina and they were hosted there.
But Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) being a dedicated man, that he was and the hard worker
and the one, who put his life on the line and his effort, his wealth, his time to fight against the religion of Allahعَزّ وجَلّ.
Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) wouldn't give up easily.
So, Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) along with his brother, Al-Haris Bin Hisham(الحارث بن هشام), they go to the Madina
because Ayaash Ibn Abi Rabi’a(عيَّاش اِبن ابي ربيعه) was their cousin and their maternal brother.
So, Abu Jahal(ابو جَهَل) and his brother, Al-Haris(الحارث) go to meet with Ayaash(عياش), who's their cousin and maternal brother.
Now Ayaash(عياش) was the one, who was accompanying Umar(عُمَر).
So, they go to the Madina and Rasool Allah ﷺ did not made Hijrah(هجرة) yet, Rasool Ullah was the last ﷺ.
So, they go to Ayaash(عياش) and they say;
Your mother, who is also their mother, made an oath that, she will not seek shade, and she will not comb her hair, until you come back.
His mother was a Mushrik(مشرك) and she made an oath that she will going to stand in the sun of Makkah and she is not gonna comb her hair.
So you see that, that’s a difficult oath!
The Sun of Makkah, and not combing your hair, very difficult thing.
فَرَّقَّ لَهَا
Umar(عُمَر) is narrating the story and he said: So, Ayaash(عياش) felt sorry for his mother.
So, I told him: Do not believe these two liars, they want to deceive you
and do not worry about your mother,
because when the heat of Makkah picks up, she is going to seek shade
and when her head gets full of lice, she is going to comb it.
Emotions cannot fool Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب).
He cannot be tricked, he said:
لَسْتُ بِالْخِبْ وَلَاالخِبْ يَخْدَعْنِي
I am not a deceiver, but in the same time, no one can deceive me.
Umar(عُمَر) suspected that these men were lying.
So, he said: Do not worry about it, and this oath that your mother made, she would not be able to carry on with it.
Lice will fill up her hair and she will have to comb it, eventually.
Ayaash(عياش) he said:
No! I have to go and fulfill the oath of my mother and I also have some money there, that I want to get,
I have some money that I want to get from Makkah.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) told him:
You know that, I am one of the wealthy men of Makkah,
I will give you half of my wealth but don't go!
Ayaash(عياش) said: No! I must go.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرإبن ألخطاب) said:
Well if you insist, this camel of mine is strong, obedient and fast, take it
and you ever see anything suspicious you can run away on its back.
And he gave him his camel, so they left Madina.
After a while, Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) told Ayaash(عياش),
O my brother! This camel of mine is horrible,
do you never mind, if we both share your camel?
Ayaash(عياش) being the naive man he is, said: Yes, yes, of course.
As soon as the camels sat down Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل) and Al-Haris(الحارث) attacked Ayaash(عياش),
they tied him up and dragged him back to Makkah.
And they put him under the Trials, the Fitnah(فِتْنَه) and he also gave up Islam.
Umar(عُمَر) said: We used to consider and they used to also consider that whoever, gives up Islam
after they know Allahعَزّ وجَلّ there is no repentance for them.
That’s it! They have no hope whatsoever.
So, when Rasool Allah ﷺ came to Madina we asked him about the situation of these men.
So Allahعَزّ وجَلّ revealed the Ayaat(آيات) in Surat az-Zumar(سورة الزمر) Verses 52 to 55.
قُلْ يعِبَادِىَ الَّذِينَ أَسْرَفُواْ عَلَى أَنفُسِهِمْ لاَ تَقْنَطُواْ مِن رَّحْمَةِ اللَّهِ
إِنَّ اللَّهَ يَغْفِرُ الذُّنُوبَ جَمِيعاً إِنَّهُ هُوَ الْغَفُورُ الرَّحِيمُ َ۞
وَأَنِـيبُواْ إِلَى رَبِّكُمْ وَأَسْلِمُواْ لَهُ مِن قَبْلِ أَن يَأْتِيَكُمُ الْعَذَابُ ثُمَّ لاَ تُنصَرُونَ َ۞
وَاتَّبِعُـواْ أَحْسَنَ مَآ أُنزِلَ إِلَيْكُم مِّن رَّبِّكُـمْ مِّن قَبْلِ أَن يَأْتِيَكُـمُ الْعَذَابُ بَغْتَةً وَأَنتُمْ لاَ تَشْعُرُونَ۞
Say, O My servants, who have transgressed against their souls!
Despair not of the mercy of Allah, For Allah forgives all sins.
For He is Oft-Forgiving, and Merciful.
And turn to your Lord in repentance and bow to His will
before the penalty comes on you, after that, you shall not be helped.
And follow the best of that of what has been revealed to you from your Lord
before the penalty comes on you, of a sudden, while you perceive not.
Umar(عمر) said: As soon those Ayaat(آيات) were revealed, I wrote them down
and by the way, Umar(عمر) was one of few men of Quraish(قريش), who was literate
and the one, who taught him was the father of Abu Sufian(ابوسفيان).
So Umar(عمر) combined many skills, physical strength, intellectual power, he was literate man,
- he was well versed in poetry, he had a very sharp mind.
Anyways, he writes down these verses,
and he sends them to Makkah to Hisham Ibn Al-Haris(هشام بن الحارث),
One of the man, who stayed behind and gave up Islam.
All what Umar(عمر) did was, write down these verses.
Hisham(هشام) said: I received this scroll and I would go to the valleys, and mountains and read the verse
and I would read it again and again and I did not understand what Umar(عمر) meant.
I didn't understand the meaning of these verses, because Umar(عمر) did not write any commentary.
The Ayaat(آيات) say that Allah is forgiving, and if you have committed wrong, against yourself, Allah will Forgive you.
So, Al-Hisham(الهشام) said: I asked Allahعزُّوَجل and I prayed to Allah to give me the understanding.
So dear brothers and sisters, when you do not understand something, pray to Allah.
You know Ibn Taymiah(ابن تيميه) used to say,
that I would recite a verse and I would go and read the tafseer(تفسير) of the Ayah(آية),
and I would read eighty different views on this particular verse but none of them would appeal to me,
so I would go out to the ruins and I would stick my face in the dirt and make Sujood(سجود)
and pray to Allahعزُّوَجل to give me the understanding
and this is the scholar Ibn Taymiah(ابن تيميه).
So, Hisham Bin Haris(هشام بن حارث) was praying to Allah to give him the understanding.
He said: Then I realized that these verses were revealed talking about us and the ones, who are in similar situations.
And I realized that Allahعزُّوَجل is giving us another chance.
And that's when, I mounted my camel and went towards Madina.
Brothers and sisters, there is very important lesson to learn here from this story of Hijrah(هجرة) of Umar(عمر) and Ayaash(عياش).
Umar(عمر) told Ayaash(عياش), don't believe them, they want to deceive you.
The important lesson to learn here is:
Never Ever Trust Al-Kuffar(الكفار).
Do Not Trust Them
You might argue and say but my neighbor is such a nice person
My classmates are very nice, my co-workers, they are just fabulous people, they are so decent, and honest.
You know the only problem is that we Muslims are giving Islam a bad name,
if these terrorists would just stop, what they are doing?
And we give them Dawah(دعوة) in the right way, everybody is gonna become Muslim.
Now, I am not going to argue that your neighbor is not nice person or your classmate
they're very well, they truly might be decent and nice people.
But brothers, when you make a judgment about Kuffr(كفر) you do not Make a judgment based on your neighbor
and then you make a Qiyas(قياس) alright, and then you generalize
and you make a judgment according to one person, that you know.
Because this person that you know is not the one, calling the shots.
And when Qur’an talks about Kuffar(كفار) it talks about the leaders of Kuffr(كفر).
The ones, who are pulling the strings.
Do not make a judgment on Kuffr(كفر) based on Jane Bow and John doe.
You don't, make it base on, Joe six pack or sally soccer-mom.
You make the judgment based on the leaders of the Al-Kuffr(الكفر).
And, these are the one's whom Allahعَزّ وجَلّ talked about in the Qur'an
and gave them the name Al-Mala'a(الملاء).
In one verse after another verse Allah talks about Al-Mala'a(الملاء).
Qur’an does not waste its time talking about the people, who are just fillings and do not make any decisions.
Qur’an talks about the decision makers on both sides,
on the Camp of good and the Camp of evil.
But the followers because they don't care, Qur’an doesn’t care about them either.
Just like in the story of As-Sabth(السبت)
when, this is a story, that happened among Bannu Israel(بنواسرائيل).
They divided into three Camps.
One Camp was committing evil, which was fishing on the As-Sabith(السابت).
The second Camp was making,
أَمرٌ بِالمَعرُوفِ وَنَهيٌ عَنِ المُنكَرِ
They were telling them, what you were doing is wrong
and then there was a third Camp, who stayed quite.
Allahعزُّوَجل told us the Fate of the evil doers,
that they were transformed into pigs and monkeys that's in Surat Al-Araf(سورة الاعراف),
and it tells us about the ones, who were preventing this evil that they were saved
and it completely ignores about the third, who did nothing.
Allahعزُّوَجل, He talks about Al-Mala'a(الملاء), Allahعزُّوَجل says:
قَالَ الْمَلَأُ مِنْ قَوْمِهِ إِنَّا لَنَرَاكَ فِي ضَلَالٍ مُبِينٍ۞
Allahعزُّوْجل says that the leaders of the people of Noah(نوح) said:
You are being deceived, you are mislead.
Allahعزُّوَجل says about Aad(عاد),
قَالَ الْمَلَأُ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا مِنْ قَوْمِهِ إِنَّا لَنَرَاكَ فِي سَفَاهَةٍ وَإِنَّا لَنَظُنُّكَ مِنَ الْكذبين۞
The leaders of people of Aad(عاد) said:
إِنَّا لَنَرَاكَ فِي سَفَاهَةٍ
We see that you have feeble mind and we think that you are a liar.
So, it just talking about the leaders.
Allahعزُّوَجل says about the people of Shoaib(شعيب)
قَالَ الْمَلَأُ الَّذِينَ اسْتَكْبَرُوا مِنْ قَوْمِهِ لَنُخْرِجَنَّكَ يَا شُعَيْبُ
وَالَّذِينَ آمَنُوا مَعَكَ مِنْ قَرْيَتِنَا أَوْ لَتَعُودُنَّ فِي مِلَّتِنَا
The leaders of the people of Sho’aib(شعيب) said: We going to drive you out of our land
you and the ones, who followed you if you don’t give up your religion.
Allahعزُّوَجل says about the people of Firauon(فرعون),
قَالَ الْمَلَأُ مِنْ قَوْمِ فِرْعَوْنَ إِنَّ هَٰذَا لَسَاحِرٌ عَلِيمٌ۞
The leaders of Firauon(فرعون), said that he Musa(موسى) is a knowledgeable sorcerer.
It also says about them,
وَقَالَ الْمَلَأُ مِنْ قَوْمِ فِرْعَوْنَ أَتَذَرُ مُوسَىٰ وَقَوْمَهُ لِيُفْسِدُوا فِي الْأَرْضِ وَيَذَرَكَ وَآلِهَتَكَ
قَالَ سَنُقَتِّلُ أَبْنَاءَهُمْ وَنَسْتَحْيِي نِسَاءَهُمْ وَإِنَّا فَوْقَهُمْ قَاهِرُونَ۞
This is talking about the people of Firauon(فرعون), who are lobbying,
they are lobbying Firauon(فرعون), and they're inciting him.
They said: You are going to leave Musa(موسى) do whatever he wants?
That is when Firauon(فرعون) said: We are going to kill him,
so they are lobbying Firauon(فرعون) to kill the believers.
These are Al-Mala'a(الملاء)
وَجَاءَ رَجُلٌ مِنْ أَقْصَى الْمَدِينَةِ يَسْعَىٰ قَالَ يَا مُوسَىٰ إِنَّ الْمَلَأَ يَأْتَمِرُونَ بِكَ لِيَقْتُلُوكَ فَاخْرُجْ إِنِّي لَكَ مِنَ النَّاصِحِينَ۞
A man came from the other end of town
to warn Musa(موسى) and tell him that the leaders are plotting to kill you,
Leave! I am giving you a sincere advise.
Brothers that’s what they are doing today!
They are plotting to kill this religion.
Don’t make Qiyas(قياس) based on your friend,
who is not a decision maker.
Allahعَزّ وجَلّ is telling you that the leaders of the Kuffr(كفر) are plotting against you
and Allahعَزّ وجَلّ says that they are plotting so much, He says:
بَلْ مَكْرُ اللَّيْلِ وَالنَّهَار
They are plotting night and day.
And there plotting is so great, Allahعَزّ وجَلّ says about it;
وَإِنْ كَانَ مَكْرُهُمْ لِتَزُولَ مِنْهُ الْجِبَالُ
Their plotting is sufficient to move the mountains from their places.
After all of this you will trust them?.
You know these nice neighbors and wonderful co-workers and friends.
All what it needed is, for Milosevic to tell them,
that the Muslims are evil people that's all what was needed
and they pounced on the Muslims like wild beasts.
This is in twentieth century Europe.
So, those who are counting on Democracy and Human Rights and the Civilized World, and Amnesty International don't be fooled.
Allahعَزّ وجَلّ is telling you that they are up to no good.
And Allahعَزّ وجَلّ tells you;
وَاللَّهُ أَعْلَمُ بِأَعْدَائِكُمْ
Allahعَزّ وجَلّ knows your enemies.
Are you going to go with what Allahعَزّ وجَلّ tells you, or you are going to go with your assumptions?
Allahعَزّ وجَلّ says;
وَدَّت طائِفَةٌ مِن أَهلِ الكِتابِ لَو يُضِلّونَكُم
Allahعَزّوجَلّ says:
وَدُّوا لَوْ تَكْفُرُونَ كَمَا كَفَرُوا فَتَكُونُونَ سَوَاءً۞
They want you to disbelieve so you would become equal to them.
وَلَنْ تَرْضَىٰ عَنْكَ الْيَهُودُ وَلَا النَّصَارَىٰ حَتَّىٰ تَتَّبِعَ مِلَّتَهُمْ
The Jews and the Christians will not be pleased, until you become like them.
How can you have trust in leaders of Kuffr(كفر) when today, today, right now, right now!
There are Muslim brothers who are in jail,
every sinister method of interrogation is used against them.
They would use against them, homosexual to rape them.
They would bring their mothers and sisters and wives
and they would rape them in front of these brothers.
Now, it’s true that it's not happening in the west but the west knows about it,
United Nations knows about it and Amnesty international knows about it and they are doing nothing.
In fact sometimes they are encouraging it.
This is something happening today.
And we have seen yesterday what happened to our brothers in Bosnia.
So Allahعَزّ وجَلّ tells you in Qur'an what you need to know
but the thing is that many of us are gullible and naive.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) knew it very well and he said:
مَا يُرِيْدُوْ اِلَّا لِيَفْتِنُوْكَ عَنْ دِيْنِكْ
All they want is to deceive you from your religion.
That’s what they are up to.
So, we need to wisen up and not be duped.
Malcolm X used to says: We have been Bamboozled.
By the way, this thing about, No! It's not going to happen to us,
you know, it’s a civilized world, democracy, human rights.
Brothers and sisters Yani(يعني) when it comes to religious freedom
Makkah may be had more religious freedom than the west today.
Before the Da'wah(دعوة) of Muhammadﷺ Makkah had Christians, it had Jews,
it has followers of the religion of Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) and they were tolerated.
There was Waraqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل), who was a Christian
there was Zaid Bin Amr Bin Nufail(زيد بن عمرو بن نوفيل)
who was on the religion of Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) and Jews used to come in and out.
But the thing is the system of Kuffr(كفر) will tolerate everything,
It will tolerate gays, lesbians, but its not going to tolerate the message of truth.
That's how the system of Shaytan(شيطان) is designed.
When it comes to, freedom of speech,
Souq Al-Akaaz(سوق عكاظ) is equal or better to speakers corner of Hyde Park?
The tradition of freedom of speech in Makkah was great.
You could go stand up and say whatever you want, nobody is gonna harm you.
It was a pretty much democratic system in Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
there wasn’t a tyrant they didn’t have this one leader, who is imposing these military rules on them.
Everyone in Makkah could do whatever they want, it was very, very free society.
But the thing is when Islam came in the scene, it was not tolerated.
Because that’s the way of Shaytan(شيطان), he will tolerate everything except the truth.
So, beware and Be cautious! Take the advice of Umar(عُمَر),
Be careful!
Do not trust the enemies of Allah.!
Especially brothers do not trust the Mouth Piece Of Shaytan(شيطان) the "Western Media".
One brother comes to you and says: You know what happened! What happened!
This! And this! And this!
Brother where did you hear it?
Reliable sources.. What? CNN!
It was a two hour documentary on CNN. Man!!, they showed everything.
BE CAREFUL!
And back to the issue of the masses of the people,
the masses of people they are decent and they are nice.
But the thing is, if they do not wake up from the dream world that they are living in
they are not gonna wake up, until they end up in Hell Fire.
And then they will blame the leaders and say: You are the one, who brought us here.
And they will ask Allahعَزّ وجَلّ to multiply the punishments on the leaders.
And there are quite a few conversations in the Qur’an that happened between the leadership and the followers.
And Allahعَزّ وجَلّ gives us the reasons. Why?
فَاسْتَخَفَّ قَوْمَهُ فَأَطَاعُوهُ ۚ إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا قَوْمًا فَاسِقِينَ۞
Allahعَزّ وجَلّ says; Firauon(فرعون) belittled his people, so they followed him,
they were people who were corrupt.
So, Allahعَزّ وجَلّ said that, the masses followed Firauon(فرعون),
Why? Because they were, Fasiqeen(فاسقين).
They had, Fasooq(فسوق) they were attached to the Duniyah(دنيا),
they were attached to their jobs,
they were attached to the status quo,
they were attached to their Shahawat(شهوات), their desires
and that mislead them, that’s how their leaders tricked them.
So, in Bosnia that’s what happened.
They were very nice,
I mean, a brother was telling me that, they use to date our women,
they used to be very close to us, neighbor to neighbor, very close.
But then Milosevic tricked them by bringing up these false legends of history and these nationalistic songs and all of that.
It inspired the people and they turned against the Muslims.
They were so gullible and naive that all what it took, were few nationalistic songs
and a few events in the history that were fabricated and not true
and they just attacked the Muslims.
That's how easy it was, to deceive these masses.
Who otherwise, before that very decent, and honest and nice people.
But the thing is that many of the people just follow what they are told.
UMAR(عُمَر) AND QUR'AN.
We said: Last session that Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب), the truth would flow out naturally on his tongue,
he was a Muhadas(محدث).
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) says about himself and this is in Al-Bukhari(بخاريْ), he says:
Allah agreed with me on three occasions, Allah Ho Akbar(الله اكبر), Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله),
Allah agreed with me, on three occasions,
Umar(عُمَر) says something and Allah agrees with him.
وَافَقْتُ رَبِّي فِي ثَلَاثْ
فَقُلْتُ: يا رسول الله، لَوْ اَتَّخَذْنَا مِنْ مَّقَامِ إِبْرَاهِيْمَ مُصَلّى
فَأنَزَلَتْ: وَاتَّخِذُوْا مِنْ مَّقَامِ إِبْرَاهِيْمَ مُصَلّى
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرإبن الخطاب) said:
Why don’t we take the standing of Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) as a place of prayer?
So, Allahعَزّ وَجَلّ revealed the verse,
And take the standing place of Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم), as a place of prayer.
وَآيَةُ الْحِجَابِ، قُلْتُ: يا رسول الله، لَوْ أَمَرْتَ نِسَاءَكَ أَنْ يَحْتَجِبْنَ
فَإِنَه’ يُكَلِّمُهُنَّ اَلْبَرُّ وَالْفَاجِرْ، فَنَزَلَتْ آيَةَ الْحِجَابْ،
I told Rasool Allah ﷺ, O Rasool Ullah, why don’t you order your women to have Hijaab(حجاب)?
Because, they are speaking to men who could be good or evil.
And that’s when the Ayah(آية) of Hijaab(حجاب) was revealed.
وَاجْتَمَعَ نِسَاءُ النَّبِي صلى الله عليه وسلم فِيْ الْغِيْرَةْ عَلِيْهِ
فَقُلْتُ لَهُنَّ: عَسَى رَبُّه’ إِنْ طَلَّقَكُنَّ، أَنْ يُبْدِلَه’أَزْوَاجَا خَيْرَا مِّنْكُنْ، فَانَزَلَتِ هَذِهِ الّآيَةْ
The wives of Rasool Allah ﷺ had jealousy
and the wives of Rasool Allahﷺ, some of them,
because of their jealousy they made this plan and they told Rasool Allah ﷺ something,
the whole thing was because of their jealousy between them.
Umar(عُمَر) caught word of that, so he went to the wives of Rasool Allah ﷺ he brought them together
and he said: If you don’t stop what you are doing?
Allahعَزّوجَلّ will replace you with better wives for His Messenger,
and he was giving them this harsh advice.
So, one of these wives of Rasool Allah ﷺ was upset and she said;
What do you think?
Rasool Allah ﷺ is unable to give us Naseeha(نصيحة), so that you come and give us Naseeha(نصيحة).
Who are you to come and give us Naseeha(نصيحة)?
Rasool Allah ﷺ could do that.
But an Ayah(آية) was revealed saying,
عَسَىٰ رَبُّهُ إِنْ طَلَّقَكُنَّ أَنْ يُبْدِلَهُ أَزْوَاجًا خَيْرًا مِنْكُنَّ مُسْلِمَاتٍ
مُؤْمِنَاتٍ قَانِتَاتٍ تَائِبَاتٍ عَابِدَاتٍ سَائِحَاتٍ ثَيِّبَاتٍ وَأَبْكَارًا۞
Allahعَزّ وجَلّ can give him, wives better than you to the end of the Ayah(آية),
These are three event which he mentions that’s not it, but there are some other events that happened.
Abdullah Ibn Obeye(عبدالله ابن ابئ), the leader of the Munafiqeen(منافقين), he was the top Munafiq(منافق) in the Madina.
When he passed away Rasool Allahﷺ wanted to lead his Janazah(جنازة) after all, what he has done.
Rasool Allah ﷺ still wanted to lead his Janazah(جنازة).
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ is standing ready to start his Salah(صلاة).
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) comes and stands in front of him,
and he says; O Messenger of Allah
You want to pray on this man, who did this and this and this and this...
He said: When I kept on going Rasool Allah ﷺ was only smiling.
When I was not stopping and I was mentioning all his evil sins,
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Move away from me, Umar(عُمَر).
Allahعَزّ وجَلّ had told me:
اسْتَغْفِرْ لَهُمْ أَوْ لَا تَسْتَغْفِرْ لَهُمْ إِنْ تَسْتَغْفِرْ لَهُمْ سَبْعِينَ مَرَّةً فَلَنْ يَغْفِرَ اللَّهُ لَهُمْ
Ask for forgiveness, for them or don’t ask for forgiveness for them
even, if you ask Forgiveness for them seventy times, Allah will not forgive them.
So, if I know that if I make Istighfaar(استغفار) seventy one times,
if I know that would help them, I would do so.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ prayed on Abdullah Bin Obaeye(عبدالله بن أبيئ).
And then he followed his Janazah(جنازة) and stood on his grave, asking Allah to forgive him.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: Rasool Allah ﷺ was surprised by my boldness.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) comes and stands infront of Rasool Allah ﷺ preventing him from, leading the Salah(صلاة).
And he argues with Rasool Allah ﷺ, until Rasool Allah ﷺ told him; Move away.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) says; A short while after that Allahعَزّ وجَلّ reveals the Ayah(آية),
وَلَا تُصَلِّ عَلَىٰ أَحَدٍ مِنْهُمْ مَاتَ أَبَدًا وَلَا تَقُمْ عَلَىٰ قَبْرِهِ ۖ
إِنَّهُمْ كَفَرُوا بِاللَّهِ وَرَسُولِهِ وَمَاتُوا وَهُمْ فَاسِقُونَ۞
At-Tauba(ألتوبة) Verse 84.
Allah says; Do not ever pray for any of them, that dies and do not stand on his grave
for they rejected Allah and His Messenger and they died as non believers.
Allahعَزّ وجَلّ is telling Muhammadﷺ never ever pray on them again.
So, it came to confirm what Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said.
In the Battle of Badr(بدر) Rasool Allah ﷺ have seventy prisoners of war.
This is first battle of Islam, so there were many new things
and the Laws weren’t revealed yet, relating to those issues.
One of them was the issue of Prisoners of War.
They have seventy prisoners of war.
What should we do with them?
As usual Rasool Allah ﷺ makes Shoora(شورى).
Abu Bakr As-Siddique رضي الله عنه said:
These are our relatives, our fathers, brothers, cousins, why don’t we ransom them?
The money that is paid is gonna strengthen the Muslims
and these men might grow one day, to become Muslim
and that would strengthen Islam.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) said: O Messenger of Allah!
I disagree with what Abu Bakr(ابو بكر) said.
I say that you should hand over to Ali(علي) his brother Aqeel(عقيل) to execute him.
You hand over to Hamza(حمزه) his brother so and so to execute him,
you hand over to me my relative to execute him,
and he went on and on.
So, Allah knows the we have no mercy in our hearts for the disbeliever.
حَتَى يَرَى الله اِنَّه’ لَيْسَ فِيْ قُلُوْبِنَا هَوَادَةْ عَلَى الْكُفَّارْ
To give a message to the believers and to disbelievers
and to show Allah that we have no mercy in our hearts for Kuffr(كفر).
Abdullah Ibn Rawaha(عبدالله ابن رواحة) said: My view is that you dig a ditch for them, a trench
and you fill it with wood and you burn them.
That was the opinion of Abdullah Ibn Rawaha(عبدالله ابن رواحة).
Rasool Allah ﷺ left and the Sahabah(صحابه) were debating which opinion would he choose
some say Abdullah Ibn Rawaha(عبدالله ابن رواحة) some say Umar(عُمَر) and some say Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
Rasool Allah ﷺ comes out and he adopts the opinion of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), that we accept ransom.
And there is a longer Hadith(حديث) in Al-Ahmad(الاحمد) relating to this.
Rasool Allah ﷺ came out and he said:
إِنَّ اللَّهَ لَيُلِينُ قُلُوبَ رِجَالٍ فِيهِ ، حَتَّى تَكُونَ أَلْيَنَ مِنَ اللَّبَنِ
وَإِنَّ اللَّهَ لَيَشُدُّ قُلُوبَ رِجَالٍ فِيهِ ، حَتَّى تَكُونَ أَشَدَّ مِنَ الْحِجَارَةِ
Allahعَزّ وجَلّ softens some hearts so they become as soft as milk
and Allahعَزّ وجَلّ makes some heart hard and strong so that they become like rocks.
وَإِنَّ مَثَلَكَ يَا أَبَا بَكْرٍ كَمَثَلِ إِبْرَاهِيمَ عَلَيْهِ السَّلَام
قَالَ : فَمَنْ تَبِعَنِي فَإِنَّهُ مِنِّي ، وَمَنْ عَصَانِي فَإِنَّكَ غَفُورٌ رَحِيمٌ۞
And the analogy of you, Abu Bakr(ابو بكر) is like Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) you are similar to Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم), who said:
Whoever follows me is from me, and whoever disobeys me, You are Forgiving and Merciful.
And you are also similar to 'Eesa(عيسى).
قالَ: إِنْ تُعَذِّبْهُمْ فَإِنَّهُمْ عِبَادُكَ ۖ وَإِنْ تَغْفِرْ لَهُمْ فَإِنَّكَ أَنْتَ الْعَزِيزُ الْحَكِيمُ۞
If You punish them they are Your servants and if Your Forgive them; You are Al-Aziz ul Hakeem(العزيزالحكيم)
وَاِنَّ مَثَلَكَ يا عمر كَمَثَلِ نُوْحْ
You Umar(عُمَر) are similar to Noah(نوح).
وَقَالَ نُوحٌ رَبِّ لَا تَذَرْ عَلَى الْأَرْضِ مِنَ الْكَافِرِينَ دَيَّارًا۞
Noah(نوح) said: O Allah do not leave any disbeliever on the face of the earth.
And you are also similar to Musa(موسى), who said:
رَبَّنَا اطْمِسْ عَلَىٰ أَمْوَالِهِمْ وَاشْدُدْ عَلَىٰ قُلُوبِهِمْ فَلَا يُؤْمِنُوا حَتَّىٰ يَرَوُا الْعَذَابَ الْأَلِيمَ۞
O Allah make their hearts sealed so that they do not believe until they see the punishment.
And then Rasool Allah ﷺ accepted, the advice of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
Later on, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab رضي الله عنه see's Rasool Allah ﷺ and Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) crying.
So, he goes to them and says: Why are you crying?
If it makes me cry, then I will cry otherwise, I will force myself to cry.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: We are crying because Allahعَزّوجَلّ, presented, me with the punishment that was going to befall us
because we accepted the ransom.
And Allahعَزّوجَلّ revealed to me the following verses.
مَا كَانَ لِنَبِيٍّ أَنْ يَكُونَ لَهُ أَسْرَىٰ حَتَّىٰ يُثْخِنَ فِي الْأَرْضِ
تُرِيدُونَ عَرَضَ الدُّنْيَا وَاللَّهُ يُرِيدُ الْآخِرَةَ ۗ وَاللَّهُ عَزِيزٌ حَكِيمٌ۞
لَوْلَا كِتَابٌ مِنَ اللَّهِ سَبَقَ لَمَسَّكُمْ فِيمَا أَخَذْتُمْ عَذَابٌ عَظِيم۞
Al-Anfaal(ألأنفال) Verse 67-68.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ says: It is not fitting for a prophet that he should have prisoners of war,
until he has caused bloodshed among the disbelievers.
You look for temporal goods of this world
but Allah looks at the hereafter and Allah is Exalted in Might and Wise.
Had it not been for previously ordainment from Allah
a severe punishment would have reached you for the ransom that you took.
So, Allahعَزّ وجَلّ is telling Muhammadﷺ this was the first time, that you fight with the Kuffar(كفار),
you should have executed them all.
You should have caused bloodshed on the land, among the Kuffar(كفار).
So, Allahعَزّوجَلّ disapproved, taking the ransom.
But Allah says that punishment was gonna come down
however, it was already ordained.
That the Ghaneema(غنيمة) is Halal(حلال) for this Ummah(امة).
So, that’s why the punishment was with held.
So Qur’an came approving the opinion of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab رضي الله عنه when it came to those prisoners of war.
ANOTHER INCIDENT:
Rasool Allah ﷺ sent a servant to call Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) and this was at noon.
In those days, they didn’t have, any locked gates, doors.
All what they had was mud houses very small.
And there would be a curtain hanging on the entrance and you just walk in.
So, Umar(عُمَر) was sleeping and part of his body was uncovered.
So, this servant comes in and he calls Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب).
Umar(عُمَر) said: O Allah! Ban allowing people to visit us, at these times.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) felt uncomfortable for this man just walking in,
and seeing him with part of his body uncovered.
Now, there is already an Ayah(آية) that was revealed of Istezaan(إستئذان)
that, you should seek permission before you go in.
However, this was for foreign people.
But with your slaves and your children and your direct family members, there wasn’t any permission, they just walk in at any time.
So, this was the servant of Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) and he walked in.
Allahعَزّ وجَلّ revealed the Ayah(آية),
يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا لِيَسْتَأْذِنْكُمُ الَّذِينَ مَلَكَتْ أَيْمَانُكُمْ وَالَّذِينَ لَمْ يَبْلُغُوا الْحُلُمَ مِنْكُمْ ثَلَاثَ مَرَّاتٍ
مِنْ قَبْلِ صَلَاةِ الْفَجْرِ وَحِينَ تَضَعُونَ ثِيَابَكُمْ مِنَ الظَّهِيرَةِ وَمِنْ بَعْدِ صَلَاةِ الْعِشَاءِ
ثَلَاثُ عَوْرَاتٍ لَكُمْ
This is Surah Nur(سورة النور) Verse 57-58.
O you who believe! Let those whom your right hands possesses and the children among you,
who have not come up age, ask not your permission
before they come to your presence on three occasions,
before morning prayers, while you undress for the noon day heat, and after the Esha(عشاء) prayer.
These are your three times of undress.
So, your children who are not over the age of puberty yet,
need to ask permission before they come into the room.
At these different three times, after Salaat-Al-Esha(صلاة العشآء)
and before Salat-Al-Fajr(صلاة الفجر)
and after Salat-Al-Zuhar(صلاة الظهر).
The Siasta time because in the hot climate of Madina, they would sleep at mid-day.
And Ibn Abbas(ابن عباس) says this is one of the Ayaat(آيات) of Qur’an that people are not practicing anymore.
He was saying about those old days, and now it's not practiced.
You need to teach your children this habit that they don’t just walk into your room at any time.
They can walk in at any other time but these three times they shouldn’t.
They should seek permission first.
We'll move to the next section which is the:
JIHAD(جهاد) OF UMAR(عُمَر) WITH RASOOL ALLAH ﷺ:
We already mentioned part of story of Badr(بدر) the prisoners of war,
there are two other incidences that happened in Ghazwat Badr(غزوة البدر),
You have Suhail Ibn Amr(سهيل ابن عمرو).
Suhail Ibn Amr(سهيل ابن عمرو) was very eloquent speaker from Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
And he used his, this ability to fight Islam.
He was one of the Prisoner Of War.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) went to Rasool Allah ﷺ and said:
O Rasool Ullah, Allow me to pluck out the front teeth of Suhail(سهيل)
so that his tongue would hang out and he wouldn’t be able to speak against you again.
Take out the front teeth, so that his tongue would just come out of his mouth
and he would not be able to talk against you again.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said:
لَا أُمَثِّلُ بِه فَيُمَثِّلُ الله بِيْ وَإِنْ كُنْتُ نَبِيَّا، وَعَسَى أَنْ يَقُوْمَ مَقَامًا لَا تَذُمُّه
He said: I am not gonna mutilate him, because Allah will mutilate me, even if I am a Prophet.
And maybe one day he will take a stand that will impress you.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ said, that I am not allowed to do something like that and then he said:
And one day he will take a stance that, you will like.
Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله)
this disbeliever, Suhail Ibn Amr(سهيل ابن عمرو), who became Muslim very late, after Sulh-Al-Hudaybiyyah(صلح الحديبيه).
When Rasool Allah ﷺ passed away, the people of Makkah, many of them commited Ridda(ردة)
and the governor of Makkah Attab Ibn Usaid(عتاب ابن اسيد), who was appointed by Rasool Allah ﷺ,
he went into hiding.
It was Suhail Ibn Amr(سهيل ابن عمرو), who stood up and invited the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) and said:
The death of Muhammadﷺ, would  only make Islam stronger
and whoever gives up Islam, I am going to behead him.
And it was only because of Suhail Ibn Amr(سهيل ابن عمرو), that the people of Makkah remained on Islam.
That was the position that Rasool Allah ﷺ was referring to.
So, don’t be in a hurry don’t punish this man, because one day this tongue will benefit Islam.
Another occasion, was Umair Ibn Wahb(عمير ابن وهب),
Umair Ibn Wahb(عمير ابن وهب) his son was taken as a Prisoner of War.
Umair Ibn Wahb(عمير ابن وهب) was a very wicked man.
Umair Ibn Wahb(عمير ابن وهب) after the Battle of Badr(بدر), he went to Madina.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) was sitting up with some of the Sahabah(صحابه), talking about the Battle of Badr(بدر).
And he saw Umair Ibn Wahb(عمير ابن وهب) approaching, with his sword hanging from his neck.
Umar(عُمَر) said: That dog,
هذا كلب عدوالله
Is the enemy of Allah and he is here for evil.
You can see the Farasah(فراسه) of Umar(عُمَر),
he said: This man came for evil.
And he immediately, rushed to Rasool Allah ﷺ, he came and said:
The enemy of Allah Umair(عمير) is here and he is upto no good.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Bring him in!
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) goes and he wraps the sword around Umair(عمير) and he ties him up
and he brings him in to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says:
أَرْسِله يا عمر
Leave him alone.
And then Rasool Allah ﷺ tells Umair(عمير),
مَا جَـاءَبِكُمْ
Why did you come?
He said: O Muhammad(محمد),
First thing that he actually said was,
اَنْعِمْ صَبَاحًا
Good Morning.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: We have a better greeting then that.
السلام و عليكم ورحمة الله وبركاته
Allah has given us something better than good night and good morning.
مَا جَاءَبِكَ يا عمير
Why did you come here?
He said: I came here to ransom my son.
He said: Umair(عمير), tell me the truth, why did you come here?
He said: I am telling you the truth that’s the only reason, why I came here.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: So, what is that sword doing on your neck?
He said:
قَبَّحَهَا الله مِنْ سُيُوْفِ وَهَلْ أَغْنَت عَنَّا شَيْئَا؟
May evil befall all of these swords, what good have they done us?
We lost in Badr(بدر).
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: No, that’s not why you came here.
The reason why you came here, is because you have met with Sufwan Ibn Umayyah(صفوان ابن امية), next to Al-Ka’aba(ألكعبه)
and you told Sufwan(صفوان), that if it wasn’t because you have daughters
and you fear for their welfare, if you die and you are in debt, you would go and kill Muhammad(محمد).
And then Sufwan Ibn Umayyah(صفوان ابن امية) told you,
I am going to take care of your daughters just as if they were mine,
and I am going to pay your debt and you agreed, to come and kill me.
That’s why you came here Umair(عمير).
Umair(عمير) said:
That conversation was witnessed by no one but me and Safwan(صفوان).
So, I testify and bear witness that there is no god but Allah and you are the Messenger of Allah.
He became Muslim.
Back in Makkah, Safwan(صفوان) was telling the people, just wait, you will just hear a very good news in few days.
You're gonna hear some very good news.
Umair(عمير) comes back and he tells Safwan(صفوان), that I have became Muslim.
it was disaster for Safwan(صفوان).
You can also notice that Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) had a very good sense of security.
Because he knew that this man is intending evil
and when he went in and grabbed him and wrapped his sword around him and took him to Rasool Allah ﷺ
and Rasool Ullah told him to leave him alone.
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) told some Ansaar(أنْصَار), he told them be careful from this man.
This man is here for an evil purpose, protect Rasool Allah ﷺ from him.
So, Umar(عُمَر) had very good sense of security, you see it, in this incident
and you can also see it, in some other stuff that we have talked about earlier.
For example, with ‘Ayaash(عياش), he told him to be careful from Abu Jahal(ابو جَهَل),
so he had a very good sense of security and this is a good thing to have and not to be duped.
Tayyeb(طيب), we'll carry on In Sha Allah Ta'ala(إن شاءالله تعالى) tomorrow
with the Jihad(جهاد) Umar Ibn Al-Khattab رضي الله عنه with Rasool Allah ﷺ.
If you have any questions we could go to some questions, yes.
Question From Audience.
No, I'm not gonna mention anything else regarding that story, But I think that the points are clear.
How do you relate that to the issue of trusting the Kuffar(كفار)?
Question From Audience.
Yani(يعني) I don't see the relationship between that and the issue of the trust of the Kuffar(كفار),
I'm not sure, I understand the question!
Question From Audience.
Okay, Tayeb(طيب) I think I understand what you're relating to.
Now, there is a difference between trust and working.
You work with Muslim and non Muslim, you work with everyone.
There's a difference here, you work with everyone!
But the trust goes to the ones, who believe in Allahعَزّوجَلّ the people of tawheed(توحيد).
And when we talk about the trust issue, and not to be deceived.
It's also relating to Aaimma Tul Kuffr(آئمة الكفر), the leadership of Kuffr(كفر).
But the masses are deceived and the Muslims need to wake them up.
The Da'wah(دعوة) that was given by Nooh(نوح), the Da'wah(دعوة) that was given by Saleh(صالح),
the Da'wah(دعوة) that was given to by Hood(هود).
Who was it given to?
It was given to Kuffar(كفار),
they invited Kuffar(كفار) and they woke them up, from their state of unconsciousness.
That is what we need to do.
Your friends, your neighbors all of these people, they could one day become Muslim,
if they woke up from that state of Unconsciousness.
So definitely there's in terms of establishing institutions for the Muslims,
work needs to be done for the Muslims, whether you're living in Muslim lands or non Muslim lands.
But the thing is that we should not put too much trust
on what we hear from the media, or the political leadership.
Because the real intentions are not really shown,
just like Abu Jahal(أبوجهل) did not show his real intentions to Ayyash(عيَّاش)
they're not showing the real intentions today.
The sisters, if you have any questions you can write them down.
And we don't want to deprive the sisters from be able to ask questions.
Yes,
Question From Audience.
This was only relating to first battle,
in the first Battle, Allah didn’t want Muhammadﷺ to take Prisoners of war
but after that the law is that it's upto the Imam(اِمَام)
to either free them without ransom, or ransom them or execute.
These are up to the Imam(اِمَام).
Sisters if you have any Questions either written or spoken, you can go ahead and ask your Question.
What is that again?
Question From Audience.
The Ayah(آية) doesn’t tell us, what happened to them?
So some of the Mufassireen(مفسرين) assumed that.
But the Ayah(آية) ignored them.
Yes, and then we'll take the Questions from there, it's one question here.
Question From Audience.
Tayyeb(طيب) the question is about the Hadith(حديث) of Rasool Allah ﷺ the best generation is my generation
but then we know that there is a Hadith(حديث) that says that
there will be, people will come at the end of time
and Rasool Allah ﷺ said: They are my brothers
and the effort of one of them is like the effort of 50 of you, the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم.
Now the general rule, is that the best generation were the earliest and then it goes down from there.
That's the general rule, but there are exceptions to every rule.
So the exception to that rule are Al-Mahdi(ألمهدي) and his followers,
the 300 plus, who will follow him are in exception.
The army that comes out from Aden(عدن) in Yemen, Rasool Allah ﷺ says:
There's gonna be army of 12,000 that will come out Aden Abyan(عدن أبين)
and they would give victory to this religion.
And they are the best between me and them.
They are the best between me and them.
The exceptions are also some of the followers of Eesa عليه السّلام.
There's in fact a narration,
my Ummah(امة) is like rain, you don’t know where the benefit of it is?
In the beginning or the end.
All rain benefits, the beginning of it and the end of it.
The beginning is Muhammadﷺ and the end is Eesa عليه السّلام.
So there are exception to that rule.
Yes brother!
Question From Audience.
Now, there is two opinions on whether his mother is relative of Khalid(خالد) or not.
There is one view, is that she is cousin of Abu Jahal(ابوجَهَل)
and the other view is that she is from Bannu Makhzoom(بنومخذوم), the family of Khalid(خالد).
However, whether they're relatives or not.
There were physical resemblances between the two.
Both were towering tall men, both were physically well built.
And it is said but maybe this is an exaggeration,
but it was mentioned that when they're sitting on their horses, their feet would touch the ground.
Allah Ho Alam(الله اعلم), they must be very tall, if that's true, but the two men were very similar.
Alright, this question wants me to repeat the names of the wives of Umar(عُمَر).
I don't have my notes for that session with me.
Yes! Umar
Question From Audience.
It wasn't really, the question was about the banning of alcohol, is that an example of Umar(عُمَر) agreeing with Qur'an.
It's not really agreeing, but he was asking Allah to show them a final answer on alcohol.
Because alcohol was banned on four stages. So Umar(عُمَر) everytime was saying,
اللهم بين لنا في الخمر بيانا شافيا
O Allah give us a final decree on Khamr(خمر), that would satisfy us,
until the final verse was revealed that Khamr(خمر) is Haram(حرام).
We know how Allah talks about not raising our voices above the voice of Muhammadﷺ
so how did Umar(عُمَر) disputed Muhammad صلوات الله وسلام عليه
in the incident of the Janazah(جنازة) of Abdullah Bin Obaeye(عبدالله بن اُبَي).
First of all the Ayah(آية)  wasn't revealed yet.
The Ayah(آية) wasn't revealed yet.
Plus, we don't really assume that he raised his voice but he was arguing with Muhammadﷺ
in a respectful way,
in respectful way.
But it was very bold, and Rasool Allah ﷺ was surprised by that boldness.
Yes!
Question from Audiences
With the issues of the history, not the Hadith(حديث).
See the scholars did a lot of work on Hadith(حديث), to give us a final answer on the strength of a Hadith(حديث).
But when it comes to the history, the work of our scholars is not that stringent and strict and detailed as it was.
So one can doubt everything.
If they want to, they can doubt everything in the history of Umar(عُمَر) or Abu Bakr(ابوبكر),
for the sake of argument, everything can be doubted.
But we just make a judgement based on the sources that we have and based on the best information
and it is something that is widely accepted among the historians that he did marry Umm Kalsoom Bint Ali(أم كلثوم بنت علي).
Yes!
Question from Audience.
No! Sorry, I might have not made it clear, Umar(عُمَر) was saying that Umair(عمير) was a dog.
He wasn't with a dog, he said that this dog is the enemy of Allah.
هذا الكلب عدُّوْ الله
He didn't have a dog.
Any other Questions!
Yes!
Yea! You're talking about the book on Khalid Ibn Walid(خالد ابن وليد),
Na'am(نعم) which is a good book on Khalid(خالد) anyway.
The question is, that there was a rivalry between Umar(عُمَر) and Khalid(خالد).
A tit for a tat thing.
How true is that I think we'll leave that until we get to the Ghazwaat(غزوات)
maybe it will become more apparent whether that's true or not.
What is your opinion on efforts to make grass root type relationships, friendships with non Muslims example,
organizing events which are not overtly Da'wah(دعوة) oriented
proselytizing, in order to humanize suffering Muslims, make us seem normal.
Normal maybe people avoid melosowich type of calamities.
Now, you could do that, but don't be very wishful in your thinking.
Know it for what it really is.
Don't overestimate.! Don't be too helpful.!
And you mentioned here melosowich, I am pronouncing it right.
The Jews they learned it the hard way.
The suffering of the Jews was in Europe, it wasn't in the Middle East or in the Muslim world.
It was in Europe, and now they're saying: Never again!
And what happened to the Jews yesterday could happen to the Muslims tomorrow.
In fact, it's already happening to them today.
So remember, and keep in mind that Europe of today, maybe it looks different than the Europe of a few centuries ago
but morally it's not very different.
When it comes to the crusading spirit, it's a spirit that could be easily revived again, if the leaders want to.
All what it takes is for the leaders to stand on the podium and call for that again.
Now, there is one problem that I have here and that is to make us seem normal.
We have to be like what Allahعَزّوجَلّ wants us to be, Allah says in Qur'an.
لاَ يَخَافُونَ لَوْمَةَ لآئِمٍ
You do not fear the blame of the blamers as a Muslim, you don't put on a show, a false image
pretend to be something just to please the other.
Allahعَزّوجَلّ says that He loves His believers when they care about nobody but Him.
You need to care about what Allah thinks about you,
not what somebody else, whether Muslim or non Muslim thinks of you.
And by the way, this is one of the qualities of Umar(عُمَر), he didn't really care at all what anybody thinks of him.
As long as it's pleases Allahعَزّوجَلّ, that's enough.
And Rasool Allah ﷺ when he was humiliated and, in At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف), when they went to give them Da'wah(دعوة)
and they threw stones at him and they sent their Sufaha(السفهاء), their kids and their slaves and their servants
to throw the rocks at Muhammadﷺ and Zaid Bin Haritha(زيد بن حارثه), and he had to run out of At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف).
What did the Rasool Allah ﷺ say in his Dua(دُعَا).
See Rasool Ullah wasn’t excepted by the people, he wasn't seen as normal.
He was seen as everything but normal.
But what did Rasool Allah ﷺ say in his Dua(دُعَا), he said:
ان لم یكن بك علي غضبٌ فلا أبالي
Oh Allah, as long as you are not angry with me, I do not care.
As long as You're pleased as long as You're happy, that's enough for me.
And that should be our approach.
Question From The Audience:
Among the Muslims, it is Wala'a(ولاء),
as long as your Muslim brother is not committing a flaw in belief.
So the issue is, maybe difference in Fiqh(فقه), difference in strategy,
difference in their association to particular movement, or line of thought.
As long as it's in those areas and it's not an issue that relates to the belief.
Then you have loyalty to them, even if there are disagreements.
And in the western context, we do not apply Hajar(ھجَر) exactly as it was usually applied before.
Hajar(ھجَر) is boycotting because boycotting was done when it was in a Islamic system.
So, everyone ends up boycotting that person or people.
And that affects them,
because, as a human being you want to have Association, you want to belong,
so that would bring them back, but here, they aren't really need you.
They don't need, they'll carry on doing what they are doing,
and they will even drift further away from Islam and it could be a fitna(فتنه) for them.
So over here, the basis is Da'wah(دعوة) not Hajar(ھجَر), Allah Ho Alam(الله اعلم).
Few questions from the sisters let's take care of them.
You will be doing this course for a month,
What is the best way of taking the lessons from this course.?
So far it has been like a story being deeply narrated
with occasionally you mentioning lessons of each phase, this is a lot to remember.
If I'm going to mention lessons on each and every point, then it's going to be a few months not one month.
By the way the timing don't take it as concrete as a month.
The plan is, we'll go through the story whenever it ends it ends,
it could be shorter than a month Allah Ho Alam(الله اعلم).
we will go with the flow.
Now, I'm assuming that all of you are intelligent, wise, brothers and sisters.
So you remember this story and you derive the lessons from it, you need to drive the lessons.
And Al-Hamdolillah(الحمدلله), you should be very capable of doing so.
In terms of position, with Allah.
Were the Companions better than the Prophets of Bannu Israel(بنو اسرائيل)?
No! The Prophets, are above everyone else.
The Sahabah(صحابه) are second best after the Prophets.
So when we say that Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) is the greatest.
He is the greatest after the Ambiyah(أنبياء) of Allah.
The lowest Nabi(نَبِي) in status is still greater than the greatest Sahabi(صحابي).
Tayeb(طيب) anything else, sister you have a question.
Yes!
All right, the Tabari(طبري), One is the history of Tabari(طبري).
The second one is a Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) by Ali As-Sallabi(علي الصلابي).
This is an Arabic it's not an English.
Yes!
Question from Audience.
Yea, This is the last question that we'll take and then we'll close.
Qur'an talks about the leadership of the camp of good and the camp of evil and then there's a third group.
Does that mean that they're blameworthy and how do we apply that to our situation today
for brothers and sisters who might not be in leadership position?
By the way, when I talked about the leadership
something I forgot to mention in the people of Thamood(ثمود), Allahعَزّوجَلّ says:
وَكَانَ فِي الْمَدِينَةِ تِسْعَةُ رَهْطٍ يُفْسِدُونَ فِي الْأَرْضِ وَلَا يُصْلِحُونَ۞
Among the people of the Thamood(ثمود), the leaders of Kuffr(كفر) were nine.
And these nine are the ones, who brought the people of Thamood(ثمود) destruction, nine people.
But anyway, you don't have to be in a leadership position that's not, what is meant.
You know appointed to a leadership position it means, when we say leader Al-Mala(ألملاء).
The people who are exerting influence, even if they're not in a position of leadership.
They could be businessmen, they could be activists,
they could be Junior politicians, they could be in the media,
they could be lawyers, they could be teachers,
it is talking about people who are exerting leadership,
the people who are directing, who are ahead of the pack.
Now,
as long as you are following the truth, it doesn't make a difference where you are.
But Qur'an warns the masses from being deceived by the leadership that's, that's the thing.
If you're a follower, make sure that you're not deceived.
I don't want you to leave with the wrong understanding that you must be a leader in order to be exempted.
This third group they did nothing about the evil, but if they did something about it
because the other camp that prevented the evildoers from doing evil they were not all the leaders
but they're doing their part, as long as you are doing your part, that's what you want to do.
You do your part according to what Allah has given you, the gifts that you have and to the best of your human ability.
That's what you need to do; Allah Ho Alam(الله اعلم).
صَلَّى الله عَلى سَيَّدِنَا محمد وَعَلى اَلِهِ وَ صَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ
سُبحانك اللهم وبحمدك نشهد الله اله الا انت نستغفرك ونتوب عليك